{"tossups": [{"question": "<b><u>A landmark with this word as the first word in its name was referred to by</u></b> <b><u>Pierre-Jean De Smet as the \"Register of the Desert.\" Edward Partridge purchased a</u></b> <b><u>piece of land in a city with this name which was to be the center of \u201cNew (+)</u></b> <b>Jerusalem,\" featuring the Temple Lot. A Wyoming rock along the Emigrant Trail that resembled Uluru is named for this word, which also names a city that was the starting (*) </b>point of many trips across the Continental Divide en route to California. For the point, what word names a Missouri city in which Harry Truman is buried?", "answer": "<b><u>Independence</u></b> (accept <b><u>Independence</u></b>, Missouri; accept <b><u>Independence</u></b> Rock)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "<b><u>These people revolted in namesake conflict after being force marched to</u></b> <b><u>Velikiye Luki [[veh-LICK-ee-yuh LOO-kee]], allying themselves with deposed regent</u></b> <b><u>(*)</u> Sophia Alekseyevna [[ah-LEX-see-YEV-nah]]. This unit made use of the </b><em><b>gulyay-</b><b>gorod</b></em><b>, a type of mobile fortification, first used at the 1552 Siege of Kazan. This unit, which was often accompanied by horsemen whose name translates to (*) </b>\"Boyar's Children,\" were gradually incorporated into the normal army by Peter the Great. For the point, name this elite unit of firearm-wielding troops of the 16th and 17th century Imperial Russian army.", "answer": "<b><u>Streltsy</u></b> (accept <b><u>Streletskoye</u></b> Voysko; accept <b><u>Shooters</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>During the La Baule speech, this leader called for democratic elections in the</u></b> <b><u>former colonies of West Africa. This leader's former prime minister and successor</u></b> <b><u>went directly against his claim that the Republic of (+)</u> France did not deport Jews during the Holocaust. This leader of the Socialist Party opposed the founding of the Fifth Republic, and he ordered the sinking of the (*) </b>Greenpeace vessel <em>Rainbow</em> <em>Warrior</em>. For the point, name this longest serving President of France who was succeeded by Jacques Chirac in 1995.", "answer": "Fran\u00e7ois <b><u>Mitterrand</u></b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This group signed the Treaty of Pontotoc [[PON-tuh-tok]] Creek, which ceded</u></b> <b><u>much of its land in Mississippi. Levi Colbert helped negotiate the removal of these</u></b> <b><u>people from one area. It\u2019s not the (+)</u> Choctaw, but after the U.S. Army abandoned Fort Washita [[wah-SHEE-tah]], this tribe became allies with the Confederacy. Much of Western (*) </b>Kentucky was purchased from this tribe. For the point, name this tribe which, with the Choctaw, Cherokee, Creek, and Seminole, is referred to as the \u201cFive Tribes of Oklahoma.\u201d", "answer": "<b><u>Chickasaw</u></b> Nation (prompt on \"Impsaktea\" or \"Intcutwalipa\")", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This battle was prompted by the decapitation of envoys whose heads were</u></b> <b><u>displayed on Bab Zuweila Gate. A feigned retreat drew the losing side of this battle</u></b> <b><u>into an ambush where they were attacked by men hidden behind trees. Fought near</u></b> <b><u>the Spring of (+)</u> Harod, this battle ended with a counterattack that brought about the death of Kitbuqa. Qutuz [[koo-TOOZ]] delivered a decisive flanking maneuver at this battle, which was fought two years after the sack of Baghdad. (*) </b>Mongol expansion westward was hampered by, for the point, what 1260 Mamluk victory fought in Galilee?", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Ain Jalut</u></b> (accept Ma'rakat <b><u>\u2018Ayn J\u0101l\u016bt</u></b>; accept Battle of <b><u>Goliath\u2019s Spring</u></b>; or Battle of the <b><u>Spring of Goliath</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>The memoir</u> </b><em><b><u>Journey Through My Years</u></b></em><b><u> was written by this politician, who as</u></b> <b><u>governor backed the Ake Law banning German-language education. This man</u></b> <b><u>defeated William Gibbs (+)</u> McAdoo to gain the nomination in an election in which he was on the losing end of the largest popular defeat since 1820. Franklin Delano Roosevelt was this man's running mate in that election, in which an opponent called for a (*) </b>\u201creturn to normalcy\u201d after the Wilson presidency. For the point, name this Democratic Ohio Congressman who lost to Warren Harding in the 1920 presidential election.", "answer": "James M(iddleton) <b><u>Cox</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>During namesake wars, these people used the \"Wagenburg\" tactic at sites like</u></b> <b><u>the Battle of Nekmir [[neck-MEER]]. A king aligned to this movement named George</u></b> <b><u>of Pod\u011bbrady [[poh-DAY-brahd] participated in the elimination of its more extreme</u></b> <b><u>faction, the (+)</u> Taborites, at Lipany. These people, led by Jan \u017delivsk\u00fd, threw Catholic magistrates out of a window during the First (*) </b>Defenestration of Prague. For the point, name these Czech proto-Protestants, a major force behind the Bohemian Reformation of the 15th century.", "answer": "<b><u>Hussite</u></b>s (accept <b><u>Kali\u0161n\u00edci</u></b>; accept <b><u>Hussite</u></b> Wars)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Passing in the Senate by a vote of 85 to 1, this agreement was originally signed</u></b> <b><u>by 31 countries. Though most historians have derided this agreement as a (+)</u></b> <b>\"worthless piece of paper,\" it established legal precedents used in the Nuremberg Trials and the United Nations Charter. Calling for the abandonment of a (*) </b>belligerent \"instrument of national policy,\u201d for the point, what 1928 treaty ostensibly outlawing war is popularly named for a French and American diplomat?", "answer": "<b><u>Kellogg-Briand</u></b> Pact (accept <b><u>Pact of Paris</u></b>; accept <b><u>General Treaty for</u></b> <b><u>Renunciation of War as an Instrument of National Policy</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>Gas attacks at Bullecourt [[buhl-leh-KOHR]] occurred at a battle near this city, which involved heavy fighting around the Scarpe River. One treaty signed in this city reconciled a longstanding feud between Charles VII [[the seventh]] of France and Phillip the Good of Burgundy, and another established a namesake (*) </b>union that allied with Spain during the Eighty Years' War. For the point, what city, the capital of the Pas-de-Calais [[pah-duh-kah-LAY]] department, is featured in the title of an Antoine de Saint-Exupery memoir, <em>Flight to</em> [this city]?", "answer": "<b><u>Arras</u></b> (accept <b><u>Aro</u></b>; accept <b><u>Atrecht</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Eunice Newton Foote joined a publishing committee in this event. Thomas</u></b> <b><u>M'Clintock read several passages of William Blackstone's law book in this event.</u></b> <b><u>Ansel Bascom did not sign this event's declaration, and (+)</u> Amelia Bloomer did not endorse it. This event occurred at the Wesleyan Methodist Chapel, and the Declaration of (*) </b>Sentiments was created in this event by several Quakers and Elizabeth Cady Stanton. For the point, name this 1848 women's rights convention in Upstate New York.", "answer": "<b><u>Seneca Falls</u></b> Convention", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>An early form of the minutemen led by future governor John Endecott</u></b> <b><u>participated in this war, burning</u> </b><em><b><u>wigwams</u></b></em><b><u> near the Thames [[temz]] River. During</u></b> <b><u>this war, the John Mason and John Underhill-led militia committed the (+)</u> Mystic Massacre, prompting their Narragansett allies to attempt to return home. The Mohawks effectively ended this war after they killed the Grand Sachem (*) </b>Sassacus as a sign of goodwill to the English colonists. For the point, name this 1630s war between New England and the namesake tribe, ending in that tribe's virtual extinction.", "answer": "<b><u>Pequot</u></b> War", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Former Warlord Long Yun fell from grace during this period after claiming it</u></b> <b><u>was the USSR's responsibility to send foreign aid to leftist nations rather than his own</u></b> <b><u>nation. This \"campaign\" was intensified during the (+)</u> Lushan Conference, expelling party member and Sino-Japanese war veteran Peng Dehuai [[deh-HWA]] for critiquing the contemporaneous (*) </b>Great Leap Forward. Deng Xiaoping and Mao Zedong led, for the point, which purge of conservative elements of the Communist Party of China, making the People's Republic a <em>de facto</em> one-party state?", "answer": "<b><u>Anti-Rightist</u></b> Campaign (accept <b><u>F\u01ceny\u00f2u Y\u00f9nd\u00f2ng</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>A series titled for the \u201cNew\u201d varieties of these works by Beadle's included</u></b> <b><u>colored covers.</u> </b><em><b><u>Malaeska: The Indian Wife of the White Hunter</u></b></em><b><u> may have been the first</u></b> <b><u>of these works, which were popular with Civil War soldiers. Nick Carter was a (+)</u></b> <b>private detective who appeared in a number of these works, which often drew from story papers. Pulp magazines and nickel (*) </b>weeklies are sometimes grouped in with these works. For the point, name these works of popular fiction whose name indicates their cheap price.", "answer": "<b><u>Dime Novel</u></b>s (prompt on \"novel(s)\")", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Misc Literature"}, {"question": "<b><u>This island's unique liqueur named Kitron, made from a local citrus strain,</u></b> <b><u>was first distilled in the 1890s in its village of Halki. Ariadne was legendarily</u></b> <b><u>abandoned by the hero (+)</u> Theseus on this island after she helped him slay the Minotaur and escape the labyrinth. This site of Mount Zeus in the Aegean was the first member of the (*) </b>Delian League to attempt to secede in the 470s BCE. For the point, name this largest island of the Cyclades island group.", "answer": "<b><u>Naxos</u></b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "<b><u>Skirmishes among those who remained at this battle occurred around Hill</u></b> <b><u>689. Rathvon Tompkins conducted risky inspections during this battle, in which one</u></b> <b><u>side was supported by a bombing campaign codenamed Operation Niagara. The (+)</u></b> <b>McNamara Line was terminated at this battle, during which Operation Charlie was conducted to evacuate the central location. William Westmoreland\u2019s focus on this battle may have drawn attention away from the buildup of forces prior to the (*) </b>Tet Offensive. For the point, name this 1968 battle fought around a Marine base in Vietnam.", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Khe Sanh</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>One person in this painting appears to be, but is not actually, stepping on a</u></b> <b><u>shorter man's foot. In this painting, Benjamin Harrison VI [[the sixth]] stood in for his</u></b> <b><u>father. Lewis (+)</u> Morris and Josiah Bartlett are among the 42 members of the central group in this painting, whose center depicts a five-man drafting committee. Found in the rotunda of the Capitol, this painting is depicted on the reverse of the (*) </b>two dollar bill. For the point, name this painting by John Trumbull depicting the signers of the title document.", "answer": "<em><b><u>Declaration of Independence</u></b></em>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "<b><u>The fourth king of this name and only ruler of the Welf Dynasty lost a dynastic</u></b> <b><u>dispute with Phillip of Swabia, in part, due to earlier being excommunicated for</u></b> <b><u>commanding Innocent III to annul the Concordat of (+)</u> Worms [[VURMS]]. A king of this name defeated the mounted archers of the Magyar [[mahj-YAR]] horde invading Bavaria at the 955 Battle of (*) </b>Lechfeld. For the point, give this name of multiple Holy Roman Emperors, including the son of Henry the Fowler and the name of a High Middle Ages \"Renaissance.\"", "answer": "<b><u>Otto</u></b> (accept <b><u>Otto</u></b> IV; accept <b><u>Otto</u></b> I; or <b><u>Otto</u></b> the Great; accept <b><u>Otto</u></b>nian Renaissance)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>The Chalcatongo tongue of this people exhibits an inability to differentiate</u></b> <b><u>between questions and statements when speaking exclusively in the language. Eight</u></b> <b><u>Deer Jaguar Claw united this culture group into one kingdom in the 11th century</u></b> <b><u>until his willing demise by ritual (+)</u> sacrifice. These people, whose name means \"Cloud Folk\" in Nahuatl [[nah-HWA-tul]], inhabit a namesake cultural region of Mexico in the states of Guerrero and (*) </b>Oaxaca [[wah-HAH-kah]]. For the point, name this pre-Colombian people of Mesoamerica, the rivals of the Zapotecs.", "answer": "<b><u>Mixtec</u></b>s (or <b><u>Mixteco</u></b>s; accept <b><u>\u00d1u\u00f9 savi</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>During this event, the Gallic Allobroges [[all-oh-BRO-gis]] people had letters</u></b> <b><u>outlining this conspiracy seized while traversing the Milvian Bridge. Much of the</u></b> <b><u>early planning for this event was done at the house of (+)</u> Sempronia, future mistress of Julius Caesar. One target of this event, Gaius Antonius Hybrida, traveled with his legate Marcus Petreius to crush the last of its forces in Picenum. A group of supporters of Sulla attempted to overthrow consul (*) </b>Cicero in, for the point, which 63 BCE conspiracy?", "answer": "<b><u>Cataline</u></b> Conspiracy (or Second <b><u>Catilinarian</u></b> Conspiracy)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "<b><u>During this man's fiscal reforms, he introduced the first \"token coin\" used in</u></b> <b><u>Europe in a thousand years, called the</u> </b><em><b><u>quartarolo</u></b></em><b><u>. With Vitale II, this leader</u></b> <b><u>attempted but failed to conduct an 1172 punitive mission against Manuel I [[the</u></b> <b><u>first]] (+)</u> Komnenos after that emperor rebuilt the Pisan and Genoese quarters in one city. This leader refused rulership of the newly created Latin Empire, instead placing his fellow crusader (*) </b>Baldwin of Flanders on the throne. For the point, name this elderly blind doge [[DOHZH]] of Venice who ordered the 1204 sacking of Constantinople.", "answer": "Enrico <b><u>Dandolo</u></b> (accept \"Henry\" in place of \"Enrico\"; accept Henricus <b><u>Dandulus</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>The Hehe Wars were fought in this colony, in which tensions flared after</u></b> <b><u>cotton quotas were created by Carl Peters. During a rebellion in this colony, castor oil</u></b> <b><u>and millet seeds formed a mixture that (+)</u> Bokero\u2019s followers believed would turn bullets into water. The aforementioned Maji Maji Uprising occurred in this colony, which contained the port city of Kilwa. In exchange for Heligoland, this colony gave up control of an island once ruled by (*) </b>Oman. For the point, name this colony that lasted from 1885 to 1919 and contained Burundi, Rwanda, and the mainland of Tanzania.", "answer": "<b><u>German East Africa</u></b> (accept <b><u>Deutsch-Ostafrika</u></b>; accept <b><u>GEA</u></b>; prompt on \"Tanzania\" before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>A rearrangement of this song by Lee Hays was completed after he heard it</u></b> <b><u>sung by Aunty Laura. One version of this song claims that \u201cthe old man is a-waiting to</u></b> <b><u>carry you.\u201d This song claims that \u201cthe riverbank makes a very good (+)</u> road\u201d and was often sung by Peg Leg Joe. The title feature of this song was another name for the Big Dipper, two of whose stars pointed to Polaris, toward which (*) </b>freedom seekers traveled after escaping their enslavers. For the points, name this folk song that was sung on the Underground Railroad.", "answer": "\"<b><u>Follow the Drinkin' Gourd</u></b>\" (accept \"<b><u>Follow the Drinking Gourd</u></b>\"; prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Misc Arts"}, {"question": "<b><u>After being mortally wounded by an arquebus, one commander at this battle</u></b> <b><u>told his subordinates to \u201ckeep beating the war drums\u201d to maintain morale. Deng</u></b> <b><u>Zilong was killed during a rescue attempt during this battle, after which a eulogy was</u></b> <b><u>delivered by Chen Li. Fought near (+)</u> Namhae Island, this battle involved one side attempting to withdraw to Pusan. Large vessels with protective armor known as (*) </b>turtle ships were used by the forces of Yi Sun-sin at this battle. For the point, name this 1598 victory that ended the 16th century Japanese invasions of Korea.", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Noryang</u></b> Point", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This document asserted that one interpretation \u201cbecame a part of the life of</u></b> <b><u>the people\u201d and \u201cconfirmed their habits, customs, traditions and way of life.\u201d This</u></b> <b><u>document was notably not signed by Estes Kefauver and Al (+)</u> Gore Sr, as well as Lyndon B. Johnson. Drafted in 1956, this declaration opposed the Supreme Court\u2019s ruling in (*) </b><em>Brown v. Board of Education</em>. For the point, name this document opposing desegregation, which was signed by congressmen like Strom Thurmond.", "answer": "<b><u>Southern Manifesto</u></b> (accept <b><u>Declaration of Constitutional Principles</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>George Kruck Cherrie was among the nineteen members of this effort, from</u></b> <b><u>which sixteen returned. A group of rubber-tappers helped the members of this effort,</u></b> <b><u>who were followed by the Cinta Larga tribe. A journey to Tapirapu\u00e3 was part of the</u></b> <b><u>first (+)</u> leg of this effort which started along the Paraguay River. A leg infection afflicted a member of this effort who was accompanied by Colonel Rondon and his son Kermit. Occurring two years after a failed (*) </b>1912 presidential campaign, for the point, what scientific expedition in Brazil was undertaken by Teddy Roosevelt?", "answer": "<b><u>River of Doubt</u></b> Expedition (accept <b><u>Roosevelt\u2013Rondon</u></b> Scientific Expedition before \u201cRondon\u201d is mentioned and prompt after; accept Expedi\u00e7\u00e3o Cient\u00edfica <b><u>Rondon-</u><u>Roosevelt</u></b> before \u201cRondon\u201d is mentioned and prompt after; accept synonyms for \"expedition\" such as \"journey\")", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>The Tokens\u2019s version of a song from this country hit #1 in 1961, but its</u></b> <b><u>original performer, Solomon Linda, died penniless. A trumpeter from this country</u></b> <b><u>recorded (+)</u> \u201cGrazing in the Grass\u201d and married Miriam Makeba. Elton John and Queen controversially performed at this country\u2019s Sun City resort. Ladysmith Black Mambazo, a group from this country, gained worldwide fame after appearing on Paul Simon\u2019s album (*) </b><em>Graceland</em>. For the point, \u201cThe Lion Sleeps Tonight\u201d was originally sung in what country\u2019s Zulu language?", "answer": "<b><u>South Africa</u></b> (accept Republic of <b><u>South Africa</u></b>; or <b><u>RSA</u></b>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Jazz"}, {"question": "<b><u>This vessel was frequently commissioned to transport troops from St. Louis to</u></b> <b><u>New Orleans along the Mississippi River. Overshadowed by the killing of John Wilkes</u></b> <b><u>(+)</u> Booth the day before, there was very little press coverage of this vessel's destruction. No one was ever held accountable for this vessel's destruction, the official cause of which was determined to be mismanagement of the (*) </b>boilers. For the point, name this steamboat whose explosion on the Mississippi River is considered the worst maritime disaster in U.S. history.", "answer": "<em><b><u>Sultana</u></b></em>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>After charging up a hundred meter hill under machine gun fire, this specific</u></b> <b><u>force was the first to take a Turkish military point during the Gallipoli Campaign</u></b> <b><u>while led by Sari Bair. This force fought a short-lived 19th century war with the (*)</u></b> <b>Sikh Empire over control of the Kashmir Valley they both previously occupied. These soldiers, who wield the </b><em><b>khukuri</b></em><b> machete, share a name with a historic kingdom on the (*) </b>Indian subcontinent located along the Trishuli River. For the point, name these soldiers who fought for the British Empire in the 19th and 20th century.", "answer": "<b><u>Gurkha</u></b>s (or <b><u>Gorkha</u></b>s; accept <b><u>Gorkha</u></b>li)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>A ballad focusing on this event features the line, \u201cfrighted with Fire-balls, their</u></b> <b><u>heads turned round.\u201d William Herbert and John Belasyse [[bell-uh-\"sighs\"]] were</u></b> <b><u>among a group of five people accused of being involved in this event. The</u></b> <b><u>strangulation of Edmund (+)</u> Godfrey further fueled this conspiracy, which was partly instigated by Israel Tongue. Restrictions on the number of Carmelite missions were imposed in the aftermath of this event, which led to perjury accusations against (*) </b>Titus Oates. For the point, name this 17th-century anti-Catholic conspiracy in England.", "answer": "<b><u>Popish</u></b> Plot", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>The marriage of a princess of this dynasty is commemorated in an annual</u></b> <b><u>celebration known as the Landshut Wedding. The Thirteen Years\u2019 War was fought by</u></b> <b><u>a member of this dynasty who wed Elisabeth of Habsburg. To distinguish between the</u></b> <b><u>last two kings of this dynasty, the father was given the nickname \"the (+)</u> Old.\" The Second Peace of Thorn ended a conflict between the Teutonic Knights and this dynasty, which was ruled by men like Sigismund and Casimir IV. Ruling after the (*) </b>Piasts, for the point, what Polish dynasty began under the reign of W\u0142adys\u0142aw II [[VWAD-iss-SWAV the second]]?", "answer": "House of <b><u>Jagiellon</u></b> [[YAH-gyeh-lohn]] or [[YAHG-yeh-wohn]] (accept <b><u>Jagiellon</u></b>ian [[YAH-gyeh-loh-NEE-an]] Dynasty; be lenient on pronunciation, including allowing a \"J\" sound at the beginning of the word)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Perhaps because he was missing his own dog \u201cSweet Lips,\" a commander at</u></b> <b><u>this battle ordered a ceasefire to return the other\u2019s fox terrier. John Laurens was</u></b> <b><u>wounded in the shoulder during this battle, two months after which the winner tried</u></b> <b><u>to engage at (+)</u> White Marsh. Wilhelm Knyphausen\u2019s forces were fired upon by troops who had marched up a road along the Schuylkill River. The battle of (*) </b>Brandywine preceded this battle, which occurred after the seizure of Philadelphia a week earlier. For the point, name this defeat in Pennsylvania for George Washington.", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Germantown</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Henry Vandyke Carter assisted the creator of this book, which was first</u></b> <b><u>published by John Williams Parker in 1858. This book's author relied on an 1832 act</u></b> <b><u>to gain access to certain unclaimed subjects from workhouses. The subtitle</u></b> <b><u>\u201cDescriptive and (+)</u> Surgical\u201d has been used in recent editions of this book, whose original author was a Royal Society fellow known for his studies of the (*) </b>endocrine system. For the point, name this medical textbook currently in its 42nd edition, whose name inspired a TV show set at Seattle Grace.", "answer": "<em><b><u>Gray\u2019s Anatomy</u></b></em> (accept <em><b><u>Anatomy: Descriptive and Surgical</u></b></em>; accept <em><b><u>Anatomy of</u></b></em> <em><b><u>the Human Body</u></b></em>; accept <em><b><u>Gray's Anatomy</u></b>: Descriptive and Applied</em>; accept <em>Henry</em> <em><b><u>Gray's</u></b></em> <em><b><u>Anatomy</u></b> of the Human Body</em>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>A CEO named Rob Lee compared this event to \u201cbig game hunting\u201d in his</u></b> <b><u>explanation of its motives. FireEye stocks rose by nearly four percent after an</u></b> <b><u>announcement that they would help deal with this event, which was carried out by a</u></b> <b><u>group with a (+)</u> \"Robin Hood\"-like image. Jennifer Granholm claimed that this event, which was carried out by DarkSide, resulted in a \u201csupply crunch\u201d rather than a resource shortage amid (*) </b>panic buying of the central good for $3 per gallon. For the point, name this attack carried out by hackers on an East Coast gas pipeline.", "answer": "<b><u>Colonial</u></b> Pipeline Ransomware Attack (accept equivalents such as \"Cyberattack\" or \"Hacking\")", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "<b><u>In a set of four principles regarding this amendment, Justice Brennan outlined</u></b> <b><u>an \u201cessential predicate\u201d that must be followed. The court case</u> </b><em><b><u>Ingraham v. Wright</u> </b></em><b><u>found a practice instituted in schools did not violate this amendment. A clause in this</u></b> <b><u>amendment was used to justify a $15,000 (*)</u> forfeiture in </b><em><b>United States v. Bajakajian</b></em><b>. The concept of \u201cdisproportionality\u201d is central to cases involving this amendment, which </b><em><b>Furman v. Georgia</b></em><b> tested regarding the (*) </b>death penalty. For the point, what amendment to the U.S. Constitution prohibits cruel and unusual punishment?", "answer": "<b><u>Eighth</u></b> Amendment to the United States Constitution (or Amendment <b><u>Eight</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>NAACP secretary Walter F. White reported on this violent incident, where he</u></b> <b><u>avoided being lynched due to passing as white while interviewing locals. The</u></b> <b><u>password (+)</u> \"We Just Begun\" was used to indicate the beginning of this violent event, which was exacerbated by national reporting of a potential Black insurrection. Occurring during (*) </b>Red Summer, this event was one of the bloodiest incidents of racial violence in the U.S. For the point, name this incident in Phillips Country, Arkansas where a local white mob killed hundreds of Black people in 1919.", "answer": "1919 <b><u>Elaine</u></b> Massacre (or <b><u>Elaine</u></b> Race Riot; prompt on \"Red Summer\" before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This former captain of Yale's baseball team served in the U.S. Naval Reserves,</u></b> <b><u>and in 2007 he operated as Legal Advisor to SEAL Team One in Iraq. In his highest</u></b> <b><u>office, this politician fired (+)</u> Broward County Sheriff Scott Israel due to his poor response to the Stoneman Douglas High School shooting. This man defeated Democratic opponent Andrew (*) </b>Gillum in a controversial gubernatorial election, and in 2021 this man banned public schools from imposing mask mandates. For the point, name this Trumpist Republican who became Governor of Florida in 2018.", "answer": "Ron <b><u>DeSantis</u></b> (or Ronald Dion <b><u>DeSantis</u></b>)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "<b><u>This country's soldiers name a war which included fighting at Gradisca</u></b> <b><u>[[GRAH-dee-skah]] and the Battle of Zaule [[ZAO-leh]], which was ended by the 1617</u></b> <b><u>Treaty of Madrid. Petar Kruzic [[KROO-zhitch]] worked for Ferdinand I and used this</u></b> <b><u>country's soldiers, known as (+)</u> Uskoks, to fight the Martolos. This country was merged with Slavonia in 1868, though Rijeka [[ree-YAY-kah]] remained separate. With four historical regions including (*) </b>Dalmatia, for the point, what is this country which sits across the Adriatic Sea from Italy?", "answer": "Republic of <b><u>Croatia</u></b> (accept Republika <b><u>Hrvatska</u></b>; accept Kingdom of <b><u>Croatia</u></b>; accept Habsburg <b><u>Croatia</u></b>; prompt on \"Habsburg Empire\" before \"Slavonia\")", "metadata": "History - European History"}], "bonuses": []}